本字幕由✿花語&花丸字幕組✿共同製作
心地いい
What a pleasant feeling.
待ちわびた王はついに現れた
The king I've been waiting for has finally appeared.
神話の時代より受け継がれた我が一族の悲願
My clan's greatest wish has been passed down since the age of legends.
To the people I left behind
in the White Dragon's village...
白龍の里に残してきた者達よ
I promise I will protect the king.
私は必ずや王をお守りしてみせる
白蛇様
White Snake.
You must be exhausted.
You haven't been on the road before.
お疲れでしょう 慣れない旅は
もう一度白蛇と呼べば その喉掻き切るぞ
Call me "White Snake" again,
and I'll tear out your throat.
此れしきで疲れるか
This isn't enough to exhaust me.
Well, I thought you must be
missing your village by now.
いや そろそろ里が恋しくなった頃かなぁと
What are you talking about?
何を言う 姫様が私を望まれたのだ
The princess asked for my assistance.
もしもの時は其方を守れとな
She said to protect you if something happens.
箱入り坊ちゃんが戦えますかね
Does a sheltered boy like you know how to fight?
静まれ
That's enough!
We're going to be traveling together,
so don't fight.
これから一緒に旅するんだから揉めないの
申し訳ありません 姫様
I'm sorry, Princess.
Hak, Ki-ja is anxious about leaving his village for the first time.
ハク キジャは初めて外に出て
不安でいっぱいなんだから 虐めない
Don't tease him!
私はそんな...
I'm not...
Ki-ja, teasing people is Hak's hobby.
Don't let it get to you.
キジャ ハクの虐めっ子は趣味だから 気にしない
趣味
My hobby?
Let's get going!
そろそろ行きますよ
はい
Okay!
Episode 11:
The Dragon's Claw
キジャ 他の龍の気配が分かるんだよね
Ki-ja, you can sense the other dragons, right?
ユンと言ったな もちろんだ
Your name is Yun, isn't it?
Of course I can.
心の目を研ぎ澄ますと 存在を感じることが出来る
By sharpening my mind's eye,
I can feel their presence.
Then tell us which one is closest.
じゃ 一番近い奴を教えて
やって見よう
I'll try.
もっとも近く感じるのは 恐らく青龍
I believe the closest one is the Blue Dragon.
誰が居るとか分かるんだ
You even know who it is?
どこ
Where is he?
そうだな
Well...
向こうが何がもやっとする
I feel something coming from roughly over there.
場所は見事に大雑把だね
Well, that's rather vague.
案ずるな
Don't worry.
皆 私の後をついてまいれ
Follow me, everyone.
I will worry!
案ずるよ
生まれて初めて外出た奴についていくのは案ずるよ
I'm worried about following someone who's never left his village before!
This may be my first time outside, but I know about the world.
外に出ずとも外の事くらい知っている
我が一族は各地に飛んで情報を集めていたのだから
My clan has visited various regions and gathered information-
Ki-ja!
キジャ
なななな なんだこのもの達は
Wh-What are these?
Who gave them permission
to make their home here?
誰の許しを得てこんな所に居を構えているのだ
W-Wait. Stop.
ま 待って 止せ
No more!
それ以上は
No! Stop!
いやめて 来ないで
白龍様は最後尾をのそっとついてきな
You can follow behind us, White Dragon.
Stay back!
I can still feel them crawling all over me.
まだ這いずり回られた感触が残っている
龍神様は虫より弱いんですね
I see that dragons are weaker than insects.
ち 違う 私はわさわさ もさもさ にゅるにゅるした物が嫌いなだけだ
N-No! I just dislike creepy crawly creatures!
我が力は誇り高き 白き龍より賜りし神の力
I have been granted the proud, divine strength of the White Dragon.
常人のものと思うな
I'm not like ordinary men.
そこにもげじげじ
Look. More bugs.
ま なんでもいいさ
Well, whatever. I'm not expecting anything from your dusty old power.
埃かぶった古の力なんぞ 充てにしてねぇんで
What?! Want to test it right here, then?
なに ならばこの場で試してみるか
Oh?
姫さん 隠れて
Princess, hide.
Hak?
ハク
どうしたの キジャ
What's wrong, Ki-ja?
誰か来る
Someone's coming.
Someone? Who?
誰かって誰さ
しかも結構な数だ
There are quite a few of them.
Their footsteps sound unrefined.
あまり品のいい足音ではないな
やばいよ ここ火の土地のご近所さんなんだから
This is bad! We're near the Fire Tribe's territory.
火の部族は敵か
Is the Fire Tribe our enemy?
ま ほぼ敵だな
Yeah, basically.
はい ハク 弓を使っていい
Hey! Hak, can I use my bow?
先生は許しません 隠れてなさい
I won't allow it. Go hide.
Let's go.
ほら 行くよ
Well, who would've thought
we'd find prey out here?
おい こんな所に獲物が居たぞ
They don't look like they have much.
なんだよ 大したもんは持ってなさそうだな
なんだ山賊か
Oh, they're just bandits.
What does that mean?
なんだとはなんだ
そうでもねぇぜ あっちに女が二人
No, look. There are two women over there.
美少年だよ
I'm a handsome young man.
この兄ちゃんなんか良い身なりだし
売れそうな面してやがる
This boy's wearing some nice clothes.
I bet we could sell him too.
おい とりあえず刻んで構わんのだろう
Hey, it's all right if I tear them apart, isn't it?
隠れてても構わんよ
Or you can hide, if you want.
誰が
Who would hide?
なんだ 兄ちゃん 震えてんのか
What's wrong, boy? Are you trembling?
心配すんなって大人しくしてりゃ殺したりしねぇから
Don't worry. If you behave, we won't kill y-
おい どうした
What happened?
I-I don't know, but his arm is boiling hot!
分かんねけど こいつの手 沸騰してるみてぇに熱い
Huh? Don't be stupid.
なにバカ言って
不用意に触れぬ方が良いぞ
You should be careful what you touch.
数千年
This power has waited thousands of years to protect its master.
主を守る為に待ち続けたこの力 私でさえ抑えが効かぬ
Not even I can restrain it.
Huh?
What is that?
なんだ あの腕
His arm!
待たせたな 白き龍の腕
Sorry to have kept you waiting,
arm of the White Dragon!
H-He's a monster!
化け物だ
あれが龍の爪の力
So that's the power of the dragon's claw.
顔に似合わず えぐいね
You're more heartless than you look.
まだ まだ足りぬ
This still isn't enough.
それでハクとやら 姫様のご命令通り 其方も守ろうか
Hak, was it? Should I also protect you,
as the Princess instructed?
お構いなく
Don't worry about me.
間に合ってるんで
I can handle myself.
Don't mess with us!
ふざけるな てめら
な なんだ此奴 普通じゃねぇ
Wh-Who are these guys?
They're not normal!
How rude.
失敬よな 普通じゃねぇのは そっちの白蛇だけだろ
The White Snake is the only one
who isn't normal!
どこ狙ってますか 白蛇様
Where are you aiming that thing, White Snake?
I told you I'd tear your throat out
if you called me "White Snake" again.
もう一度白蛇と呼べば喉を掻き切ると言ったはずだ
気にすんなよ 趣味なんだから
Don't let it get to you.
It's just my hobby.
しかしそれ ちょっと興奮しるぎじゃねぇの 目立ち過ぎ
Anyway, aren't you getting a bit too excited?
You're attracting too much attention.
姫をお守りするのが至上の喜び そなたこそ その大刀邪魔だ
Nothing delights me more
than protecting the princess.
It's your blade that's getting in my way!
四龍ってのは一途だね
You dragons certainly are devoted, aren't you?
Why do you protect the princess, then?
では其方は何のために姫を守るのだ
会ったばっかの他人に放すか バカ
I'm not telling someone I just met, idiot.
I-Idiot?
バ バカだと
行くぜ
Let's go.
I thought he was a helpless human,
but he's incredibly strong.
こやつ 非力な人間と思っていたが なんと言う力
I hate to admit it, but he may be
as strong as the dragon's arm.
認めたくはないが 龍の腕と互角に近い威力では
They're strange. They're definitely strange!
彼奴等変 絶対変
キジャはこの世の者とは思えないし
It's as if Ki-ja isn't of this world,
and the Thunder Beast's speed isn't even human.
雷獣も人間技じゃないよ あの速さ
Do you want to be useful?
役に立ちたい
Hak told me not to do it.
ハクがダメって言ったもの
我慢
I'm restraining myself.
でもこう言う時の為に練習したんでしょう
But didn't you practice for a time like this?
俺の計算によれば
According to my calculations,
今のあんたの飛距離ならあそこ
雷獣を後ろから狙ってる奴
that guy coming up behind the Thunder Beast should be within your range.
もう少し上に向けて
Aim a little higher.
今だ
Now!
やった
All right!
Yun, that was amazing!
You're a better teacher than Hak!
ユン凄い ハクより教え方上手
人のだと分かるんだよな 自分だとうまく当たらない
It's easy to help others.
I can hardly hit anything myself.
大人しくしてな 嬢ちゃん達
Stay still, girls.
人質になって貰うぞ
You're going to be my hostages.
姫さん無事か
Princess, are you all right?
ありがとう
Thank you.
面倒くさい
What a pain.
もう 終わったの
It is over already?
其方何人倒した
How many did you defeat?
Huh? I don't remember.
覚えてね
I defeated twenty-eight.
私は28だ
Then I defeated forty.
じゃ 俺40
Liar! You said you didn't remember!
嘘をつけ
覚えてないと言ったではないか 大体そんな人数いなかっ...
Besides, there weren't even that many-
キジャ 大丈夫
Ki-ja! Are you all right?
Yes. I fought a little too hard.
はい 少々暴れ過ぎました
もっと洗練された闘いをお見せするはずだったのに
I meant to fight more elegantly.
Actually, I like that the white dragon god has such a bloodthirsty fighting style.
いや 俺はいいと思うぜ
白き龍神様のその血生臭い闘いっぷり
I'm thrilled.
嬉しいね
At the castle, no one could keep up with me.
城に居た頃は本気で俺についてくれる奴は居なかった
Someday, I hope we can fight-
一度手合せ...ねぇか
ハク
Hak!
死んだか
Did he die?
He isn't dead!
死んでない
You idiot. You opened your wound.
バカ 傷開いちゃってるよ
His injury hasn't healed yet.
本当は傷治ってないんだよ
しれっとしてるけど ボロボロなんだから
He acts like he's okay, but he's still a mess.
こんな体であんな動きを
He moved so quickly, with those injuries?
信じられんこの男 化け物か
This man is unbelievable.
Is he a monster?
あんたに言われたくないと思うよ
He probably wouldn't want to hear that from you.
日が傾いてきたね
The sun is setting.
何処か寝る場所探さないと
We should find somewhere to sleep.
Is there an inn around here?
この辺に宿があるのか
野宿だよ
Under the stars.
Under the stars?
野宿
これだからぼんぼんわ
This is why I can't stand rich kids.
白龍様は最後尾をてれっとついてきな
Just follow behind us, White Dragon.
って何してんのお姫様
What are you doing, Princess?!
だってハク動けないのよ 運ばないと
Hak can't move. We have to carry him.
キジャ凄い
Ki-ja, that's amazing!
龍の腕は常人の何十倍もの力がありますので
The dragon's arm is ten times stronger than an ordinary person's.
Uh, it's just my right arm, actually.
いえ 右手だけなんですけど
大丈夫ですよ この者は
He'll be all right.
Huh?
えん ハクは強いもの
Yeah. Hak is strong.
だから 今は守られてばはりだけど 何時かは私が守りたい
He protects me all the time now,
but someday, I want to protect him.
You are strong, despite living
in the castle your whole life.
姫はずっと城におられたのに お強いですね
強くなんかないわ
I'm not strong.
しかし 山賊にもあまり動じておられなかった
But you weren't disturbed by the bandits.
そうね
You're right. I'm not afraid of bandits.
山賊は怖くない あの夜以上に怖いことは 私にはないの
Nothing could terrify me more than that night.
Hey!
早く
Hurry up!
行こう
Let's go.
Perhaps it's because of the White Dragon's blood that I was granted to protect King Hiryuu,
これは 緋龍王を守る為
与えられた白龍の血のせいだろうか
支えて差し上げたい
but I wish to guard the back of this frail girl,
強くあろうとする 泣きだしそうな か弱い背中を
who tries to be strong even though
she's on the verge of tears.
これはなんだ
What is this?
夕食ですけど 何か
It's dinner. Is there a problem?
夕食 これはさっき山道に生えていた まさかの雑草ではないか
Dinner? These are weeds that were growing on the mountain path!
雑草じゃないよ ちゃんと食べられる山菜だから
They aren't weeds!
They're mountain vegetables you can eat.
虫を入れなかっただけありがたく思えな
You should be grateful I didn't add any insects.
Insects? You eat insects?
虫 其方虫を食すのか
虫は栄養あるの
Insects are nutritious.
Are you all right with this food, Princess?
姫様は平気なのですか この様な食事
虫はまだ食べられないけど だいぶ慣れたわ
I still can't eat bugs,
but I've gotten used to most of it.
だって私...
After all...
嫌がってる暇なんてなかったし
I've had bigger fish to fry.
But since Yun arrived, the food has gotten better!
でもユンが来てから かなり食事が美味しくなったんだから
Twitch.
ハクと二人の時はもう酷くて
When it was just Hak and me, it was awful.
あら どうして泣いてるの
Huh? Why are you crying?
Princess, your journey has been so harsh.
姫様 よほど過酷な旅を
What was that about my cooking?
俺の飯がなんだって
Hak, you're awake?
ハク 起きたの
聞き捨てなりませんね
I can't let that one slide.
Is your wound okay?
傷大丈夫
My wound? What are you talking about?
傷 何の事です
それより俺の飯がなんですって
Anyway, what did you say about my cooking?
Cooking? What are you talking about?
飯 何の事
あ お腹すいた
Oh, are you hungry?
You're starting to dodge my questions.
躱すようになってきたじゃねか
Can you move? Do you want me to feed you?
体 動かせる 食べさせてあげようか
はい 口開けて
Here. Open your mouth.
姫様 そのような雑用は私めが
Princess, allow me to perform this menial task.
White Snake, don't butt in at the good part.
白蛇てめ いいとこ邪魔すんな
姫様に食べさせて貰うなど図々しい
How dare you make the princess feed you?
さて 食べ終わったら青竜の居場所なんだけど
If you've finished eating, I'd like to discuss the Blue Dragon's location.
キジャ 青龍の気配は
Ki-ja, can you sense the Blue Dragon?
向こうが何かもやっと
I feel something over there.
Yeah, okay. Sorry to bother you.
はい お手数をおかけました
青龍って白龍と同じく里があるの それとも一人
Does the Blue Dragon have a village like the White Dragon, or does he live alone?
それがよく分からないのだ
I'm not really sure.
各地に居る同胞からの情報だと
I have some information from
my compatriots living abroad.
Long ago, the Blue Dragon clan lived secretly in the Earth Tribe's territory.
青龍の一族は昔 地の部族の土地に隠れ住んでいたらしい
だが ある時を堺に
However, the Blue Dragon village suddenly disappeared, and the clan went missing.
青龍の里は忽然と消え 一族も行方不明になってしまったと
消えた でも滅びではいないんでしょう
Disappeared? But they weren't destroyed, right?
目と閉じれば 青き龍の鼓動を確かに感じる
When I close my eyes, I can feel the pulse of the Blue Dragon.
イクスが白龍以外は移動してるって言ってた
Ik-su said the other dragons move around.
たぶん 青龍一族は里ごと 何処かに引っ越したんだ
The Blue Dragon's clan must
have moved somewhere.
Ki-ja is pointing east-northeast
toward the Fire Tribe's land.
キジャの示す方向は東北東 火の部族の土地
I'd say there are about six locations where the village might be.
なら 里がありそうな場所は 六ヶ所かな
Yun, have you been there?
ユン 行った事あるの
ないよ でも
No, but the largest city after Saika is here.
Saika
この辺りは彩火の都に次ぐ大きな町があるし
There are merchant roads and
aristocratic villas in this area.
ここは商団が行き交う道や 貴族の別宅があるからね
Saika
それ以外で目立たず人も通らない土地となると
There are only about six other places that are
infrequently traveled and away from human eyes.
六ヶ所くらいに絞られるって事
凄い ユンって本当になんでも知ってるのね
Amazing! You really do know everything, Yun.
坊や扱いしないでくれる 一つしか違わないのに
Would you stop treating me like a little kid?
We're only one year apart.
よし 野郎共
All right, boys!
明日から本格的青龍探しだ つぅ訳でお休みなさい
Tomorrow we'll start searching for the Blue Dragon!
Anyway, goodnight.
Goodnight?
お休みって えっ ここで
Wait, here?!
Goodnight.
お休み
Wait.
ちょっ 待っ
うっせぇ 白蛇
Shut up, White Snake.
What?
げっそり
Haggard
キジャ 綺麗な顔が大変よ
Ki-ja, your beautiful face looks awful!
お見苦しいところを
I'm sorry you had to see that.
Hey, there's a bug on your back!
おい 背中に虫いんぞ
キジャ 待ちなさい ハクの嘘だから
Ki-ja, wait! Hak is lying!
静かにしな 愉快な珍獣共
Be quiet, you jolly exotic beasts.
いい これから人里に入るんだから
Listen up. We're about to enter a village.
しかも火の部族の土地だから 目立つんじゃないよ
And we're in Fire Tribe territory,
so don't draw attention to yourselves!
Okay.
はい
Red-haired Princess
Former General
Dragon's Claw
Silver Hair
Red-haired Princess
Dragon's Claw
無理だけど
Of course that's not possible.
Dragon's Claw
キジャ
Ki-ja...
ここにはいない
He isn't here.
そう簡単にはいかないか
I guess it won't be that easy.
じゃ次はここから十里先の...
Next, we'll go forty kilometers ahead to...
待って そこはダメだ
Wait, we can't go there.
火の部族の軍の訓練場になっている
That's a training ground for the Fire Tribe army.
Huh?
What about here, then?
じゃ ここは
That area was recently developed.
そこは最近開拓されて
I'm glad we didn't go there.
行ったらやばかったね
キジャ どうしたの
Ki-ja, what's wrong?
Nothing.
いえ
決まったよ
We've reached a decision.
It's a bit of a walk,
but we're down to three possibilities.
ちょっと歩くけど 候補地は三つに絞れた
The village will probably be one of them.
多分そこに里がある
Really?
本当
You know a lot about this area, Thunder Beast.
意外と詳しいね 雷獣
Well, I was a general.
ま 一応将軍でしたから
各部族の軍事とか変化には敏感なのよ
I'm sensitive to changes in the tribes and their armies.
今度教えてよ
Tell me more sometime.
Sure thing.
ま いいぜ
じゃ 行こう
Let's go.
キジャ
Ki-ja?
ここも居ない
Not here, either.
ここも
Or here.
キジャ どう
Ki-ja, anything?
ここもダメか
He isn't here, either?
向こうからもやっと
I feel something from over there.
What? He's still farther away?
へ また向こう
おかしいな それらしき所には行ったのに
That's odd. We visited all the likely places.
まさか青龍 国境超えたんじゃないだろな
The Blue Dragon didn't cross the border, did he?
Maybe your nose is congested, White Snake.
鼻が詰まってんじゃねぇか白蛇
鼻で嗅ぎ分けてるのではない
I'm not sniffing him out with my nose!
姫様 足を痛めたのですか
Princess, did you hurt your leg?
大丈夫 ちょっと疲れただけ
I'm all right. I'm just a little tired.
飲んで
Drink this.
美味しい なにこれ
It's good! What is this?
琵琶の果実酒 飲むと疲労回復
Loquat juice. It eases fatigue.
三つ葉を足に貼っとくから 今日はもう休みな
I'll wrap your legs in honeywort.
You should rest for today.
Yun, you're amazing!
ユン凄い 物知り
You know so much!
H-How can they sleep in a place like this?
な なぜ このような所で眠れるのだ
皆 疲れたのだ
They're all tired.
何日も身を隠し 回り道をしながら歩き続けたのだから
They've been walking off the beaten trail for days while staying concealed.
私がもっとはっきりと四龍の居場所を感じる事が出来れば
If I could detect the dragons' locations more clearly,
the princess wouldn't have to exhaust herself.
姫様をあそこまで疲れさせてしまう事はないのに
ハクやユンの知識と知恵に頼るしかないとは
I have to rely on Hak and Yun's
knowledge and wisdom.
It's so frustrating.
悔しい
Blue Dragon, brother of dragon's blood...
青龍よ 龍の血を持つ兄弟よ
呼んでいるのだぞ
I've been calling out to you all this time.
ずっと ずっと...
我々の主が探しおられるのだぞ
Our master is searching for you!
其方もそこで待っているのだろう
You're waiting there, aren't you?
王を渇望しているのだろう
You'are waiting for the king, aren't you?
何時の間にか眠っていたか
I fell asleep.
なんだ
What was that?
姫様
Princess...
It's the middle of the night.
こんな夜中に
Princess-
姫...
邪魔すんな
Don't disturb her.
姫様は何時から弓を
When did the princess begin
practicing with a bow?
She's been practicing every chance she gets since before we met you.
あんたに会う前から 暇さえあればな
多い時は一晩200本
She shoots up to two hundred arrows a night.
200...
Two hundre-
Keep it down.
大声だすな
なぜあの様な無茶を
Why does she push herself so hard?
私が居るのだから 武術など必要ないのに
She has me. She has no need for martial arts.
Yeah, the princess has me,
so she doesn't have to do anything.
俺がいるからな 姫さんは何もしなくていいんだ
だが 姫さんは己の無力を許さない
But the princess finds her helplessness inexcusable.
父を殺され 城を逃れ
Her father was killed,
and she was exiled from the castle.
それでもこの世界で生き抜く為に
She's ashamed of her weakness.
一人で何もできない自分を恥じで
It drives her to find out what she must do...
in order to survive in this world.
何をすべきかもがいてる
You don't stop the princess
from wielding a weapon?
そなたは止めぬのか 姫様に武器など
I don't want her to fight.
闘わせたいわけじゃない
However, I'm conflicted,
でも困ったことに 見ていたいとも思う
because I also want to watch her struggle like a human being.
人間らしく 足掻く姿を
Damn these insects!
こんな虫など 虫など
あの方にお役に立ちたい お役に立ちたい
I want to help her.
I want to be useful to her.
今は守られてばかりだけど 何時かは私が守りたい
He protects me all the time now,
but someday, I want to protect him.
あの方も同じなのだ
She's just like me.
よし 今日こそ首根っこ引っ掴んでやるぞ 青龍め
All right! I will find you today, Blue Dragon!
キジャ 今日は眠れた
Ki-ja, did you get any sleep last night?
Huh? Ah, um...
え あ あの
疲れてるでしょう
You're tired, aren't you?
I can tell that sleeping outside bothers you, and you haven't been getting enough rest.
野宿に慣れなくてずっと休んでないみたいだったから
大事にして
Take care of yourself.
キジャが元気じゃないと旅は進まないんだから
We can't make progress
if you're not feeling well.
姫様
Princess...
Am I useful to you?
私は お役に立てているのでしょうか
Of course! No one could replace you!
当然 キジャの代わりなんていない
Blush
Ba-dum
なんだ 胸が苦しい
What is this? My chest hurts.
Ba-dum
また龍の血が興奮しているのであろうか
Is the dragon's blood excited again?
Ba-dum
分かった
I got it!
ユン
Yun?
The Blue Dragon's village! I missed it!
青龍の里だよ 盲点だった
人なんか住めないと思ってたから でもやっぱりいたんだ
I didn't think anyone could live there,
but there is a place!
It's right on the border...
国境ぎりぎり
あの岩山にね
in those mountains.
The Blue Dragon lives there.
あそこに 青龍が
wakaru kai
Do you see
muriyari demo sakuhin de tsutaetokitai koto wo
What I'm trying so hard to convey through my work?
mukashi to kawaranai daro
It's always been this way, hasn't it?
yomizurai kashi mo haikei mo
The same obscure lyrics and background
sasaeru da to ga erasou ni sa
I've always talked ideals
nando mo nando mo itta kedo
Like supporting others
kotoba no karusa omoishiru no wa
I hope you don't realize too early
hayasuginai you ni
How irresponsible I was being with my words
yuki ga tsumetai wake nante
There's a reason why the snow is so cold
boku no te ga hito yori atsui kara
Since my hands are warmer than others'
kimi no sono te wo tsunaida toki
When I hold your hand
atatakai wo hikidasu tame
I'll be able to bring out the warmth in you
Next Time
闇の中で触れたその手はとても優しくて暖かった
The hand I touched in the darkness
was so gentle and warm.
Next time, Akatsuki no Yona, episode 12:
次回 暁のヨナ 第十二話
Episode 12:
Blindfolded Dragon
目隠しの龍
Blindfolded Dragon.